Latin American Painting Photograph Collection of the Arts Library, Yale University
Yale University Arts Library
Latin American Painting Photogaph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 50
Yale University Arts Library
3.33
8 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Latin American paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work. The individual artist portion is preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Dutch paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Painting, Latin American; Photographs; Reproductions
- General Latin America (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
- Argentina. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 21 (Box 1)
    - Basaldua, Hector, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Bermudez, Jorge, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Borraro, Luis, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Butler, Horacio, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Campos, Molina, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Cornet, Ramon Gomez, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Fader, Fernando, 1882-1935., 3 (Box 1)
    - Guttero, Alfredo, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Larranga, Enrique de, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Le Parc, Julio, 1928-., 2 (Box 1)
    - Maccio, Romulo, 1931-., 1 (Box 1)
    - Marteau, Augusto, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Pettouroti, Emilio, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Peuyrredon, Prilidiano, 1823-1870., 2 (Box 1)
    - Roux, Guillermo, 1929-., 1 (Box 1)
    - Soldi, Raul, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Spilimbergo, Lino E., 1896-., 1 (Box 1)
- Bolivia. (Box 1)
  - Anonymous., 9 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 3 (Box 1)
    - Berdecio, Roberto, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Obregon, Alejandro, 1920-c.1991., 1 (Box 1)
    - Sotomayor, Antonio, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 15 (Box 1)
    - Holguin, M. Perez, c.1660-1724., 15 (Box 1)
- Brazil. (Box 1)
  - Anonymous., 2 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 11 (Box 1)
    - Amaral, Tarsila do, 1886-1973., 1 (Box 1)
    - Becker do Valle, Rosina, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Boulet, Susan Seddon, 1941-., 1 (Box 1)
    - Cavalcanti, Emiliano di, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Dias, Antonio, 1944-., 2 (Box 1)
    - Noemia, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Segall, Lasar, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Taunay, Nicolas Antoine, 1755-1830., 3 (Box 1)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 12 (Box 1)
    - Portinari, Candido, 1903-., 12 (Box 1)
- Chile (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 1 (Box 2)
    - Roa, Israel, XX C., 1 (Box 2)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 16 (Box 2)
    - Matta, 1912-., 16 (Box 2)
      Also known as Roberto Matta-Echaurren.
- Colombia (Box 2)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings of works by Andres Santa Maria, and a folderof miscellaneous clippings of works by Pedro nel Gomez.
  - Anonymous., 6 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 1 (Box 2)
    - Cuna, L. A., XX C., 1 (Box 2)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 22 (Box 2)
    - Botero, Fernando, 1932-., 22 (Box 2)
- Ecuador (Box 2)
  - Anonymous., 1 (Box 2)
- Guatemala (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 1 (Box 2)
    - Merida, Carlos, 1891-., 1 (Box 2)
- Mexico (Box 2)
  - Anonymous., 85 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous and 1 clipping folder, 2 (Box 2)
    - XV Century., 20 (Box 2)
    - XVII Century., 2 (Box 2)
    - XVIII Century., 52 (Box 3)
    - XIX Century., 9 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 42 (Box 3)
    - Angel, Abraham, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Arrieta, Jose Agustin, 1802-1879., 2 (Box 3)
    - Arteaga, Sebastian Lopez de, 1610-1653., 1 (Box 3)
    - Atl, Dr., 1875-1964., 1 (Box 3)
    - Barreda, Ignacio Maria, XVIII C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Becerra, S. P. de, XVII C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Camarena, Gonzalez, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Chavez Morado, Jose, 1909-., 1 (Box 3)
    - Clausell, Joaquin, 1866-1935., 2 (Box 3)
    - Correa, Juan the Younger, XVIII C., 3 (Box 3)
    - Cuevas, Jose Luis, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Enriquez, Nicholas, active 1738-1770., 2 (Box 3)
    - Gerson, Juan, XVI C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Herran, Saturnino, 1887-1918., 1 (Box 3)
    - Herrera, A. Miguel de, XVIII C., 3 (Box 3)
    - Juarez, Jose, c.1615-1667., 1 (Box 3)
    - Juarez, Juan Rodriguez, 1676-1728., 4 (Box 3)
    - Juarez, Nicolas Rodriguez, 1667-1734., 1 (Box 3)
    - Jurado, Juan Jose, XVIII C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Lopez, Andres, active 1797., 1 (Box 3)
    - Lopez, Carlos Clemente, XVIII C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Martinez, Francisco, Active 1721-1736., 1
    - Martinez-Pedro, Luis, XX C., 2 (Box 3)
    - Merida, Carlos, 1891-1985., 2 (Box 3)
    - O'Gorman, Juan, 1905-., 1 (Box 3)
    - Peryns, Simon de, XVI C., 2 (Box 3)
    - Ruiz, Antonio, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Suarez, Gerardo, XIX C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Velasco, Jose Maria, 1840-1912., 1 (Box 3)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 282 (Box 4)
    - Cabrera, Miguel, 1695-1768., 3 (Box 4)
    - Castellanos, Julio, XX C., 3 (Box 4)
    - Charlot, Jean, 1898-., 3 (Box 4)
    - Covarrubias, Miguel, 1902-., 12 (Box 4)
    - Galvan, Jesus Guerrero, 1910-., 3 (Box 4)
    - Kahlo, Frida, 1910-1954., 11 (Box 4)
    - Meza, Guillermo, XX C., 2 (Box 4)
    - Montenegro, Roberto, 1885-., 2 (Box 4)
    - Orozco, Jose Clemente, 1883-1949., 67 (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 18 (Box 4)
      - Guadalajara., 7 (Box 4)
      - Hanover, NH., 21 (Box 5)
      - Mexico City., 11 (Box 5)
      - New York., 10 (Box 5)
    - Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957., 125 (Box 5)
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 5)
      - Paintings., 120 (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous locations or locations not noted., 60 (Box 6)
        - Cuernavaca., 14 (Box 6)
        - Detroit., 13 (Box 6)
        - Mexico City., 23 (Box 6)
    - Siqueiros, David Alfaro, 1898-1974., 15 (Box 7)
    - Tamayo, Rufino, 1900-1991., 23 (Box 7)
    - Villalpando, Cristobal de, active 1669-1714., 13 (Box 7)
- Peru (Box 7)
  - Anonymous., 49 (Box 8)
- Uruguay (Box 8)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 22 (Box 8)
    - Blanes, Juan Manuel, 1830-1901., 1 (Box 8)
    - Figari, Pedro, 1861-, 14 (Box 8)
    - Torres-Garcia, Joaquin, 1895-., 7 (Box 8)
- Venezuela (Box 8)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 6 (Box 8)
    - Poleo, Hector, XX C., 1 (Box 8)
    - Reveron, Armando, 1889-1954., 1 (Box 8)
    - Soto, Jesus Raphael, 1922-., 4 (Box 8)